Register of the Donald Marquand Dozer Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Donald Marquand Dozer Papers,
1893-1981
70011
Hoover Institution Archives
145 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 4 card file boxes, 8 envelopes, 1 video cassette, 1 phonorecord, 3 phonotapes (61.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, memoranda, notes, printed matter, and audio-visual material, relating to American foreign policy during World War II; postwar loyalty-security programs; government secrecy in the State Department; American foreign policy in Latin America; various aspects of Latin American history and society; and the Panama Canal treaty of 1978. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Dozer, Donald Marquand
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1905 June 7 Born, Zanesville, Ohio
1941-1943 Research analyst, Latin American Branch, Office of Strategic Services
1943-1944 Liaison officer, Office of Lend-Lease Administration
1944 Foreign trade analyst, Foreign Economic Administration
1944-1947 Research analyst and Assistant Chief, Analysis Section, Division of American Republics, Department of State
1947-1949 Acting Chief, Division of Research for American Republics, Office of Intelligence Research, Department of State
1948 january State Department representative to the Second Latin American Intelligence Conference, Panama Canal Zone
1948 March-April Assistant Technical Secretary, United States delegation, Ninth International Conference of American States, Bogota, Colombia
1949-1951 Coordinator, special intelligence project involving Latin America area for Joint Chiefs of Staff, Office of Intelligence Research, Department of State
1949-1951 Lecturer, Strategic Intelligence School, National Military Establishment, Washington, D.C.
1950-1951 Consultant on Latin America, Brookings Institute
1951-1956 Assistant to Chief, Division of Historical Policy Research, Office of Public Affairs, State Department
1956-1959 Lecturer, Department of History, University of Maryland and Montgomery Jr. College
1959-1964 Associate Professor of History, University of California, Santa Barbara
1964-1972 Professor of History, University of California, Santa Barbara
1971 Fulbright Lecturer to Argentina
1972 Received Alberdi-Sarmiento Prize, Argentina
1968-1977 Vice Chairman, American Revolution Bicentennial Commission of California
1980, august 4 Died, Santa Barbara, California
United States. Department of State.; Audiotapes.; Internal security--United States.; Latin America--Foreign relations--United States.; Latin America--History.; Latin Americirca; Official secrets--United States.; Panama Canal.; Panama.; Phonorecords.; United States--Foreign relations--Latin Americirca; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government.; Video tapes.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, circa 1930-1977
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketches, bibliographies, letters, clippings, certificates, will, and other miscellany relating to the career of Donald M. Dozer.
  - General
    - Biographical sketches and bibliographies, 1942-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Certificates. Includes several letters, 1969-1976 (Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1945-1977 (Folder 3)
    - Miscellany, Selective service materials, letters, will, directories, student evaluation, postcards with descriptions of Harvard University and other miscellany, circa 1930-1974 (Folder 4)
  - Employment
    - General. Employment, search for
      - General
        - General. Miscellanous notes, clippings, and reference lists (Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, circa 1933-1973
          - General. NOTE: Includes correspondence with Senators Styles Bridges, Ralph E. Flanders and George D. Aiken and a variety of significant scholars and educators, including Arthur M. Schlesinger, Herbert Bolton, Charles Tansill, Philip E. Mosely, Howard F. Lowry, William L. Langer
            - circa 1933-1956 (Folder 6-11)
            - 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
          - American College Bureau (Mrs. Charles E. Goodell), 1949-1959 (Folder 6)
      - Assistant Secretary of State for Latin American Affairs, 1968-1969
        - General. Application, clippings and miscellaneous background materials (Folder 7)
        - Correspondence. Includes William P. Rogers, letters to Richard Nixon (and a form reply), Ronald Reagan, George Murphy, Miles DuVal, Roger Robb, Maurice H. Thatcher (Folder 8-9)
    - Academic appointments
      - General, 1957-1958 (Folder 10)
      - University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB). Administrative materials, and correspondence, including Clark Kerr, Vernon I. Cheadle, Samuel B. Gould, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Education/University of California, 1959-1978 (Folder 11-12)
      - Fulbright-Hays Visiting Lectureship, Relates primarily to Dr. Dozer's participation in an exchange teaching program in Argentina, 1971. SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/1971/ "The Meaning of Revolution in Argentine History and United States History", 1959-1974
        - Correspondence, 1956-1974 (Folder 13-15)
        - Orientation materials, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Text. Applications, reports and course syllabi (Folder 2)
      - American Graduate School of International Management, Glendale, Arizona, Also includes letters relating to Dr. Dozer's participation in an exchange teaching program in Japan, 1975., 1972-1976 (Folder 3)
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1926-1979
  General note
  General correspondence of Donald M. Dozer arranged alphabetically; correspondence related to specific subjects is organized under relevant subject headings. Includes letters neither to nor from Donald M. Dozer. Much correspondence is also found in the other series.
  - General
    - General, Arranged chronologically within each alphabetical grouping, 1944-1979
      - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - A-P (Folder 5-19)
      - R-Z (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Family correspondence, Letters written by Dr. Dozer while traveling, 1960-1973 (Folder 5)
  - Andrews, J. Cutler, 1936-1972 (Folder 6)
  - Ashbrook, John M. (M.C.), 1968-1972 (Folder 7)
  - Barber, G. Russell, 1968-1971 (Folder 8)
  - Baxter, James P., III, 1936-1956 (Folder 9)
  - Beveridge, Albert J., 1926 (Folder 10)
  - Borah, William E. (Senator), 1926 (Folder 11)
  - Bowman, George A., 1927-1975 (Folder 12)
  - Braden, Spruille, 1955-1977 (Folder 13)
  - Bromsen, Maury A., SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/1958/"Benjamin Harrison, President of the United States"/Correspondence, 1951-1962. (Folder 14)
  - Buckley, William F., 1965-1968 (Folder 15)
  - Bunche, Ralph, 1949-1950 (Folder 16)
  - Byrnes, James F., 1947 (Folder 17)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Fund for the Republic, Inc.), 1960-1962 (Folder 18)
  - Compton, Arthur, 1950 (Folder 19)
  - Compton, Wilson, 1953-1964 (Folder 20)
  - Contreras, Belisario, 1959-1967 (Folder 21)
  - Crane, Philip M. (M.C.), 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dall, Curtis B., 1968-1970 (Folder 2)
  - D'Evelyn, Morton N., 1972 (Folder 3)
  - Dunn, Waldo H., 1930-1973 (Folder 4-5)
  - Engle, Clair, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Fisher, Sydney N., 1961-1964 (Folder 7)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1972-1976 (Folder 8)
  - Gewehr, Wesley, 1957-1961 (Folder 9)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1964-1977 (Folder 10)
  - Hancock, Ralph, 1957-1970 (Folder 11)
  - Henderson, John E. (M.C.), 1970 (Folder 12)
  - Howard, Robert D., 1949-1962 (Folder 13)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1926 (Folder 14)
  - Humphreys, Robert (Republican National Committee), 1956-1964 (Folder 15)
  - Hussey, Roland, 1953-1958 (Folder 16)
  - Johnston, Olin D. (Senator), 1958 (Folder 17)
  - Kaiser, Chester, 1955-1970 (Folder 18)
  - Kerr, Clark, 1964 (Folder 19)
  - Kimmel, Husband E., 1968 (Folder 20)
  - Kinnaird, Lawrence and Lucia, 1962-1972 (Folder 21)
  - Kubek, Anthony, 1956-1967 (Folder 22)
  - Lagomarsino, Robert J. (M.C.), 1967-1977 (Folder 23)
  - Lawrence, Louis, 1951-1956 (Folder 24)
  - Lewis, John C., 1937 (Folder 25)
  - Long, Hamilton, 1957-1960 (Folder 26)
  - Loughran, Clayton, 1959-1976 (Folder 27)
  - Marquand, Hilary A., 1963-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - McSweeney, John (M.C.), 1949 (Folder 2)
  - Meese, Edwin, 1968 (Folder 3)
  - Messolonghites, Louis, 1970-1975 (Folder 4)
  - Meyer, Frank (National Review), 1962-1972 (Folder 5)
  - Mills, Sheldon T., 1961-1964 (Folder 6)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1970-1971 (Folder 7)
  - Nelson, Frederic (Saturday Evening Post), 1958-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1969 (Folder 9)
  - Possony, Stefan T., 1962-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Powell, Enoch, 1973 (Folder 11)
  - Rafferty, Max, 1962-1972 (Folder 12)
  - Reagan, Ronald, Includes associates, 1967-1979. (Folder 13)
  - Richardson, Gilbert, 1965-1971 (Folder 14)
  - Rippy, J. Fred, 1959-1971 (Folder 15)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1967-1974 (Folder 16)
  - Schmitz, John G. (M.C.), 1971 (Folder 17)
  - Schneider, Norris, 1960-1972 (Folder 18)
  - Seldon, Arthur, 1972-1974 (Folder 19)
  - Shafroth, John F., 1966 (Folder 20)
  - Shera, Jesse, 1949-1974 (Folder 21)
  - Smoot, Dan, 1960-1970 (Folder 22)
  - Stebbins, Richard, 1949-1953 (Folder 23)
  - Taft, Robert A., Relates primarily to the job search, 1951-1953. (Folder 24)
  - Tate, Ben E., 1952 (Folder 25)
  - Teague, Charles M. (M.C.), 1961-1973 (Folder 26-27)
  - Templeton, Kenneth, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Institute for Humane Studies, 1957-1966. (Folder 28)
  - Van Natta, Thomas F., 1962-1964 (Folder 29)
  - Waller, William, 1972 (Folder 30)
  - Watts, V. Orval, 1961-1962 (Folder 31)
  - Welch, Robert, 1959-1979 (Folder 32)
  - Wheeler, Burton K. (Senator), 1953 (Folder 33)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE, circa 1930-1980
  Drafts, manuscript copies, printed copies, proofs and transcripts of speeches and writings by Donald M. Dozer, with related correspondence, notes and source materials. Arranged chronologically (NOTE: Materials related to Dr. Dozer's involvement in the World War II diplomatic papers publication controversy are in a separate series, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE-B, described below).
  - General
    - Speeches
      - General
        - General
          - General. Correspondence, clippings, newsletters and flyers relating to speeches given by Donald Dozer, for which transcripts are not present, 1947-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
          - Undated
            - General. Includes one in Spanish (Folder 5-10)
            - Latin America and the Panama Canal (Folder 11-14)
        - "The Constitution and Individual Liberty" (Folder 15)
        - "Labels". Printed copy and announcement (Folder 16)
        - "Maryland in the Civil War" (Folder 17)
        - "United States and Latin America" (Folder 18)
      - Media Broadcasts
        - Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Texts. Otherwise unidentified
          - Latin American economic development. Transcript; SEE ALSO: PHONOTAPE CASSETTE (Folder 2)
          - Panama Canal. Two different sets of questions and answers (Folder 3)
    - Writings
      - General
        - General
          - General. Correspondence and clippings relating to publishing, unidentified manuscripts, and invitations to contribute, 1941-1980 (Folder 4-5)
          - Miscellaneous. Verses, children's stories, fiction, religion (Folder 6-10)
        - Undated
          - General (untitled). Includes material prepared for the Emergency Committee to Save the Panama Canal (Folder 11)
          - "Court-Ordered Busing Unconstitutional" (Folder 12)
          - "History of Maryland" (Folder 13)
          - "The Nostalgia of the New Deal" (Folder 14)
          - "Our Isthmian Canal in Central America" (Folder 15)
          - "Our Position in Panama" (Folder 16)
          - "The Panama Canal and the United Nations" (Box 9, Folder 1)
          - "Panama Canal Crisis Demands Action" (Folder 2)
          - "Personal Statement by the Special Representative of the Queen" (Folder 3)
          - "The Policy of the Tolerant Neighbor" (Folder 4)
          - "Positive Vestiges in the First Vargas Administration: An Exploratory Essay" (Folder 5)
          - "Take W.P.A. Off Relief" (Folder 6)
          - "The United States Constitution and the Panama Canal Treaties" (Folder 7)
        - Book reviews, Primarily correspondence; reviews that were published, or consisted of three or more pages are listed separately, 1949-1980 (Folder 8-9)
        - Clippings, Interviews or published references to Dr. Dozer's work, 1962-1977 (Folder 10)
        - Letters to Editors, Letters, clipping, 1950-1977 (Folder 11)
  - "Some Aspects of Bismarck's Diplomacy, 1864-1870," Typescript, circa 1930 (Folder 12)
  - "John Myles", Dictionary of American Biography, Vol. XIII, American Council of Learned Societies, Carbon typescript with letter, 1934 (Folder 13)
  - West Coast General Strike, Apparently two distinct manuscripts: the shorter, earlier one (three drafts) appears to have been intended for expansion into a book-length work, of which only the first few chapters were begun (fourth draft). Notes for, and preliminary work on, later chapters, form the bulk of the General/Notes category., circa 1938
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1934-1938 (Folder 14)
      - Notes and fragments. (NOTE: Subject categories in quotations represent the preservation of Dr. Dozer's file folder notations, rather than actual titles)
        - General (Folder 15-16)
        - "Historical Background" (Folder 17-19)
        - "National Longshoremen's Board, Hearings and Awards" (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
        - Statistics (Folder 4)
        - "Waterfront conditions" (Folder 5)
      - Source material (primarily printed material; SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE MATERIALS/Box 148). Newsletters, speech transcripts, clippings, Executive Order #6580, pamphlets by Dalton Trumbo, Harry Bridges, and William F. Dunne, The Great San Francisco General Strike, pamphlets by the Waterfront Employers Union of San Francisco, and newsletters, serials and pamphlets by the Industrial Association of San Francisco, 1931-1953 (Folder 6-8)
    - "The General Strike of on the Pacific Coast", 1934
      - Draft #1. Holograph (Folder 9-10)
      - Draft #2. Typescript (Folder 11)
      - Draft #3. Holograph and typescript (Folder 12)
    - "Labor Upheaval on the Pacific Coast" (Draft #4)
      - "Introduction and Bibliography." Outline, fragments, and notes (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - 1. The Setting. Typescript (Folder 2)
      - 2. The Companies. Holograph (Folder 3)
      - 4. (?) The Grievances. Holograph (Folder 4)
      - 5. (?) The General Strike. Holograph (Folder 5)
      - 8. (?) The Aftermath. Holograph (Folder 6)
  - Review of Ernest S. Griffith, History of American City Government: The Colonial Period, Maryland Historical Magazine, Typescript with cover letter, 1938 September (Folder 7)
  - "Teaching Counsel One Hundred Years Young," Harvard Educational Review, Typescript copy, 1939 September (Folder 8)
  - Review of N.W. Stephenson and W.H. Dunn, George Washington, Maryland Historical Magazine, Typescript draft, 1940 June (Folder 9)
  - "The Background of the Havana Conference," Typescript and clipping, 1940 (Folder 10)
  - Review of Wilbur C. Phillips, Adventuring for Democracy, Frontiers of Democracy, Serial issue, 1940 November 15 (Folder 11)
  - "United States Relations with South America," Typed transcripts of radio broadcasts, 1940 November 27 and December 12 (Folder 12)
  - "Pan-American Solidarity in Our Time!" Maryland Alumni News, Serial issue, 1940 December (Folder 13)
  - "Maryland," World Book Encyclopedia, circa 1941
    - Correspondence, 1941-1947 (Folder 14)
    - Typescript and miscellany, 1941-1943 (Folder 15)
    - Revisions (additions). Typescript, cover letter, holograph report, 1944-1946 (Folder 16)
  - Radio broadcast for Maryland Day, Typescript, 1941 March 25 (Folder 17)
  - Review of J. Fred Rippy, The Caribbean Danger Zone, Military Affairs: Journal of the American Military Institute, Typescript draft, 1941 Summer (Folder 18)
  - "Building Western Hemisphere Unity," Dynamic America, Serial issue, 1941 August (Folder 19)
  - "Diplomatic Phases of the Last Peace," Speech typescript and letter, 1941 October 19 (Folder 20)
  - "Secretary of State Elihu Root and Consular Reorganization," Mississippi Valley Historical Review, Typescript, correspondence with William A. Williams and others, and notes, 1942 December 1942-1963 (Folder 21)
  - "Beginnings of Japanese-American Friction," The Dalhousie Review (Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia), Reprint and letter, 1943 July (Folder 22)
  - "Anti-Expansionism During the Johnson Administration," Pacific Historical Review, Reprint and letters, 1943 September 1942-1943 (Folder 23)
  - Review of Ralph V. Harlow, The Growth of the United States, Mississippi Valley Historical Review, Typescript, 1943 December (Folder 24)
  - "Wanted: A New Democratic Solidarity," Typescript and letter, 1944 March (Folder 25)
  - "The Caribbean Islands and the War: A Record of Progress in Facing Stern Realities," American Historical Review, Carbon typescript and letter, 1944 July (Folder 26)
  - "The Gap Between Government and People," Public Opinion Quarterly, Reprint, correspondence with Arthur M. Schlesinger and others, review/editorial, 1945 Spring 1945-1948 (Folder 27)
  - "The Opposition to Hawaiian Reciprocity," Pacific Historical Review, Reprint and correspondence, 1945 June 1944-1946 (Folder 28)
  - "American Opposition to Territorial Expansion, " circa 1946 (expansion of doctoral dissertation). Typescript, 1865-1895
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1933-1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous. "The Anti-Imperialist League". Unidentified holograph draft (Folder 2)
      - Non-printed source material
        - General. Notes, speech transcript (Henry A. Wallace), State Department press release and newsletter, typescript (copy) of a report by John Patterson, "The United States and Hawaiian Reciprocity, " and the State Department, "United States Intervention in Mexican Presidential Politics, 1840-1930,", 1867-1870, 1932-1951 (Folder 3)
        - Notes (primarily from archival or private collections), undated
          - General. Index cards, SEE: OVERSIZE MATERIALS/Boxes 144-147
          - Bayard, Thomas F., Holograph, 1886-1887 (Folder 4)
          - Cleveland, Grover, Holograph, 1884-1893 (Folder 5)
          - Croffut, William A., Holograph, 1899-1900 (Folder 6)
          - Reid, Whitelaw, Typescript, 1891-1892 (Folder 7)
          - Schurz, Carl, Holograph, 1869-1870 (Folder 8)
          - Willis, Albert S., Typescript copies of letters to W.Q. Gresham, 1894-1895 (Folder 9)
      - Printed source materials. Clippings, reprints, newsletters, reproductions of newspaper illustrations, 1931-1956 (Folder 10-12)
    - Table of Contents and Preface (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1. Background, 1776-1865 (Folder 2)
    - 2. Anti-Expansionism in the Johnson Administration, 1865-1869 (Folder 3)
    - 3. Resistance to President Grant's Projects, 1865-1871 (Folder 4)
    - 4. Rise of the Anti-Expansionist Tradition, 1865-1880 (Folder 5)
    - 5. Opposition to Expansion in the Pacific, 1869-1876 (Folder 6)
    - 6. Campaign against Hawaiian Reciprocity, 1876-1888 (Folder 7)
    - 7. The Challenge to Commercial Reciprocity and the New Canal Policy, 1880-1885 (Folder 8)
    - 8. Anti-Expansionism and the Samoan Islands, 1877-1890 (Folder 9)
    - 9. The Tradition Triumphant, 1889-1892 (Folder 10)
    - 10. Anti-Expansionism and the Hawaiian Revolution, 1892-1894 (Folder 11)
    - 11. Anti-Expansionism and Anti-Imperialism, 1894-1895 (Folder 12)
    - Appendices (Folder 13)
  - "Rise of the American Anti-Imperialist Tradition after " circa 1946. Typescript article with correspondence, 1865 (Folder 14)
  - "Teachers Militant--The Battle for Academic Freedom in Argentina," Bulletin of the American Association of University Professors, Typescript draft, correspondence, and typescript copies of State Department memoranda, 1946 Winter 1945-1949 (Folder 15)
  - "Elihu Root and International Arbitration," Arbitration Journal, Typescript draft and correspondence, 1947 Spring 1943-1947 (Folder 16)
  - "Pathfinder of the Amazon," Virginia Quarterly Review, Typescript, correspondence and an excerpt from a biography of Matthew F. Maury, 1947 Autumn 1888-1968 (Folder 17)
  - "Matthew Fontaine Maury's Letter of Instruction to William Lewis Herndon," Hispanic American Historical Review, Correspondence, typescript drafts and notes, including one holograph copy and one typescript copy of letters from M.F. Maury, 1948 May 1850-1948 (Folder 18)
  - "Benjamin Harrison and the Presidential Campaign of 1892," American Historical Review, Reprint and correspondence, 1948 October 1947-1949 (Folder 19)
  - "Crisis in the Cold War," Typescript and letter, 1949 (Folder 20)
  - "Roots of Revolution in Latin America," Foreign Affairs, Reprinted in Readings in Latin American Social Organization and Institutions, Olen E. Leonard and Charles P. Loomis (eds.), 1949 January 1953
    - General. Correspondence, citations (clippings), comments and source materials, 1948-1953 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Draft. Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - Review of Henry Luther Stoddard, Presidential Sweepstakes: The Story of Political Conventions and Campaigns, American Historical Review, 1949 January (Folder 4)
  - "The Tariff on Books," Mississippi Valley Historical Review, Correspondence and typescript, 1949 June 1948-1954 (Folder 5)
  - "New Directions in Latin America,", 1950-1953
    - Article. Typescript, comments by State Department reviewers, and letters, circa 1950 (Folder 6)
    - Speech. Program, correspondence, typescript and clippings, 1952-1953 (Folder 7)
  - "Truman's Emergency," Holographs, 1950 December (Folder 8)
  - "Political Factors of Latin America," Typescript, letters, and earlier versions entitled "Lost Continent?" and "Our Policy Toward Latin America", circa 1951 (Folder 9)
  - "The Western Hemisphere," Major Problems of United States Foreign Policy, 1951-1952, Brookings Institute, Typescript and letter (Folder 10)
  - Review of Samuel Flagg Bemis, John Quincy Adams and the Foundation of American Foreign Policy, Review of Inter-American Bibliography, Typescript draft and memoranda, 1951 January-March (Folder 11)
  - "Two Diplomatic Histories--An Appraisal," Review of Inter-American Bibliography, Reprint, 1951 July-December (Folder 12)
  - Review of Jane Lucas de Grummond, Envoy to Caracas: The Story of John G.A. Williamson, Nineteenth-Century Diplomat, Pennsylvania History, Typescript draft, cards and memorandum, 1951 October (Folder 13)
  - "America's New Foreign Policy,", 1951 December
    - General